<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"><channel><title>Posts on Naomi News</title><link>https://naomi.unaids.org/news/posts/</link><description>Recent content in Posts on Naomi News</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-gb</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 26 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://naomi.unaids.org/news/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>All model fit and calibration options will now be set by default</title><link>https://naomi.unaids.org/news/posts/default-options/</link><pubDate>Mon, 26 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://naomi.unaids.org/news/posts/default-options/</guid><description>All model fit and calibration options now have default values. The defaults are the options used in the final naomi fit from last years estimates process. Note that if the value of any of the options used last year is no longer a valid option (for example if the prevalence survey selected last year is not uploaded this year) then we attempt to set a default from information in the input data.</description></item><item><title>New output plot: Comparison barchart</title><link>https://naomi.unaids.org/news/posts/comparison-barchart/</link><pubDate>Wed, 31 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://naomi.unaids.org/news/posts/comparison-barchart/</guid><description>We&amp;rsquo;ve released a new output plot type which you can use to review model results. This can be accessed from the &amp;ldquo;Review output&amp;rdquo; step under a new &amp;ldquo;Comparison&amp;rdquo; tab.
You can use this plot to review differences between input data and model outputs. Using the filters you can select which indicator to visualise and which variable to display on the x-axis. We recommend viewing indicators such HIV prevalence, ART coverage and key ANC indicators by sex and region.</description></item><item><title>Model output zip can now be loaded to view outputs</title><link>https://naomi.unaids.org/news/posts/project-load/</link><pubDate>Mon, 18 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://naomi.unaids.org/news/posts/project-load/</guid><description>A model output zip can now be reloaded into the app to allow users to review the output plots, see the options used and review the input data.
The new feature can be accessed from the &amp;ldquo;File&amp;rdquo; menu in the top left hand side of the screen from both the model fit and projects page. This feature will completely restore the project from the outputs, you can use it to share a model output with a collaborator so that they can see the results, see the input data and options used and even refit the model.</description></item><item><title>Project notes added to output zip</title><link>https://naomi.unaids.org/news/posts/project-notes-zip/</link><pubDate>Mon, 20 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://naomi.unaids.org/news/posts/project-notes-zip/</guid><description>Project and version notes are now included in the model output zip. Now, when you write notes on the project page these will added to the output zip in a file &amp;ldquo;notes.txt&amp;rdquo;. The notes file contains the name, last modified time and content of the the project and every version.</description></item><item><title>Data exploration: a standalone input data viewer</title><link>https://naomi.unaids.org/news/posts/data-exploration/</link><pubDate>Wed, 24 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://naomi.unaids.org/news/posts/data-exploration/</guid><description>We&amp;rsquo;ve added a new standalone data exploration mode. You can access this at https://naomi.unaids.org/explore You can use this new mode to view your input data early in the estimates process within a simplified UI. The data exploration has less strict data validation than the Naomi model fit and so can be used to diagnose data issues before model fitting. The new mode is available to users without a Naomi account via the &amp;ldquo;Continue as guest&amp;rdquo; button on the landing page.</description></item></channel></rss>