<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"><channel><title>Posts on Naomi News</title><link>https://naomi.unaids.org/news/posts/</link><description>Recent content in Posts on Naomi News</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-gb</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 14 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://naomi.unaids.org/news/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Input Comparison</title><link>https://naomi.unaids.org/news/posts/input-comparison/</link><pubDate>Thu, 14 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://naomi.unaids.org/news/posts/input-comparison/</guid><description>We&amp;rsquo;ve added a two new input review plots into Naomi.
You can now review a comparison of Spectrum to Naomi input data. This plot shows the numbers from the input ANC and ART files aggregated to the same level as the Spectrum file. Use this to inspect any differences between input numbers to identify potential data quality issues.</description></item><item><title>Load output zip from ADR</title><link>https://naomi.unaids.org/news/posts/adr-rehydrate/</link><pubDate>Thu, 24 Oct 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://naomi.unaids.org/news/posts/adr-rehydrate/</guid><description>We&amp;rsquo;ve added a new feature to allow you to import an output zip from the ADR. Clicking this will list all datasets in the ADR you have access to which have an output zip. It will list datasets from this years estimates and last years, so you can use this to review last years approved estimates.
To import an output zip, log in and go to the project page and click the &amp;ldquo;New&amp;rdquo; button to find the &amp;ldquo;Import output ZIP from ADR&amp;rdquo; option.</description></item><item><title>Map plots show base map</title><link>https://naomi.unaids.org/news/posts/map-background/</link><pubDate>Wed, 23 Oct 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://naomi.unaids.org/news/posts/map-background/</guid><description>The input and output choropleth plots will now show a base map behind the country plots. You will be able to see more context for your country including water bodies.
You can click the button &amp;ldquo;Show base map&amp;rdquo; to toggle the map background on or off.</description></item><item><title>New input file: DMPPT2 VMMC coverage outputs</title><link>https://naomi.unaids.org/news/posts/dmppt2-input-file/</link><pubDate>Fri, 19 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://naomi.unaids.org/news/posts/dmppt2-input-file/</guid><description>We&amp;rsquo;re pleased to announce an update to Naomi that allows you to upload the DMPPT2 workbook tool into Naomi on the upload inputs page. If you upload this file, Naomi will extract VMMC indicators and add them into the PEPFAR datapack file included in the Naomi output zip.
Previously, users had to download their output from Naomi, upload it to Spectrum, wait for the VMMC indicators to be added, and then download the updated file.</description></item><item><title>New Table Tab in the Model Outputs page</title><link>https://naomi.unaids.org/news/posts/table-tab/</link><pubDate>Fri, 01 Dec 2023 09:47:28 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://naomi.unaids.org/news/posts/table-tab/</guid><description>We are proud to release a new tab to the model outputs page. This can be accessed from &amp;ldquo;Model Outputs&amp;rdquo; page under the &amp;ldquo;Table&amp;rdquo; tab.
The table tab lets you filter and pivot the data by selecting our presets which currently contain &amp;ldquo;Sex by area&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;Sex by 5 year age groups&amp;rdquo;. There are some filters baked into the table itself to let you search a particular age group or district.</description></item><item><title>Input time series now shows missing data</title><link>https://naomi.unaids.org/news/posts/time-series-missing/</link><pubDate>Thu, 30 Nov 2023 15:47:28 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://naomi.unaids.org/news/posts/time-series-missing/</guid><description>We&amp;rsquo;ve made an update to the input time series to more clearly show missing input data. The input time series is used to display time trends of input programme data, the plots show the raw data and aggregates at admin levels. If the input data has a missing value for a region we now display this as a greyed out circle. When an aggregate contains a region with a missing value previously that was shown as 0.</description></item><item><title>Help videos now available</title><link>https://naomi.unaids.org/news/posts/help-videos/</link><pubDate>Tue, 31 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://naomi.unaids.org/news/posts/help-videos/</guid><description>2 years ago we created some instruction videos about how to use Naomi. We&amp;rsquo;ve now added a link from the &amp;ldquo;Online support&amp;rdquo; menu in the header to the videos. We&amp;rsquo;ve plans to update and expand these video tutorials going forward so stay tuned for updates! You can watch the videos here.</description></item><item><title>Vue3 upgrade</title><link>https://naomi.unaids.org/news/posts/vue3/</link><pubDate>Sun, 24 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://naomi.unaids.org/news/posts/vue3/</guid><description>We&amp;rsquo;ve updated the front end framework we use for building Naomi. Naomi used to be built on Vue2 which is reaching end of life. This has been upgraded to the new Vue3. You should see no major changes to the UI, let us know if you encounter any problems.</description></item><item><title>New download: Comparison report</title><link>https://naomi.unaids.org/news/posts/comparison-report/</link><pubDate>Thu, 24 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://naomi.unaids.org/news/posts/comparison-report/</guid><description>We&amp;rsquo;ve released a new model output download, the comparison report.
The report is an html file containing details and interactive plots comparing Naomi estimates to input data. This includes details of the data used in the comparison and interactive plots to explore differences between model outputs and input data. You can share this with people who do not have access to Naomi to give them an overview of model comparisons.</description></item><item><title>All model fit and calibration options will now be set by default</title><link>https://naomi.unaids.org/news/posts/default-options/</link><pubDate>Mon, 26 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://naomi.unaids.org/news/posts/default-options/</guid><description>All model fit and calibration options now have default values. The defaults are the options used in the final naomi fit from last years estimates process. Note that if the value of any of the options used last year is no longer a valid option (for example if the prevalence survey selected last year is not uploaded this year) then we attempt to set a default from information in the input data.</description></item><item><title>New output plot: Comparison barchart</title><link>https://naomi.unaids.org/news/posts/comparison-barchart/</link><pubDate>Wed, 31 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://naomi.unaids.org/news/posts/comparison-barchart/</guid><description>We&amp;rsquo;ve released a new output plot type which you can use to review model results. This can be accessed from the &amp;ldquo;Review output&amp;rdquo; step under a new &amp;ldquo;Comparison&amp;rdquo; tab.
You can use this plot to review differences between input data and model outputs. Using the filters you can select which indicator to visualise and which variable to display on the x-axis. We recommend viewing indicators such HIV prevalence, ART coverage and key ANC indicators by sex and region.</description></item><item><title>Model output zip can now be loaded to view outputs</title><link>https://naomi.unaids.org/news/posts/project-load/</link><pubDate>Mon, 18 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://naomi.unaids.org/news/posts/project-load/</guid><description>A model output zip can now be reloaded into the app to allow users to review the output plots, see the options used and review the input data.
The new feature can be accessed from the &amp;ldquo;File&amp;rdquo; menu in the top left hand side of the screen from both the model fit and projects page. This feature will completely restore the project from the outputs, you can use it to share a model output with a collaborator so that they can see the results, see the input data and options used and even refit the model.</description></item><item><title>Project notes added to output zip</title><link>https://naomi.unaids.org/news/posts/project-notes-zip/</link><pubDate>Mon, 20 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://naomi.unaids.org/news/posts/project-notes-zip/</guid><description>Project and version notes are now included in the model output zip. Now, when you write notes on the project page these will added to the output zip in a file &amp;ldquo;notes.txt&amp;rdquo;. The notes file contains the name, last modified time and content of the the project and every version.</description></item><item><title>Data exploration: a standalone input data viewer</title><link>https://naomi.unaids.org/news/posts/data-exploration/</link><pubDate>Wed, 24 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://naomi.unaids.org/news/posts/data-exploration/</guid><description>We&amp;rsquo;ve added a new standalone data exploration mode. You can access this at https://naomi.unaids.org/explore You can use this new mode to view your input data early in the estimates process within a simplified UI. The data exploration has less strict data validation than the Naomi model fit and so can be used to diagnose data issues before model fitting. The new mode is available to users without a Naomi account via the &amp;ldquo;Continue as guest&amp;rdquo; button on the landing page.</description></item></channel></rss>